It may sound surprising, but you don’t have to be interested in fashion, or even in history, to enjoy Dress Codes: How the Laws of Fashion Made History.
这听起来也许令人惊讶，但你不必对时尚感兴趣，甚至不必对历史感兴趣，也能喜欢《着装规范：时尚法则如何创造了历史》这本书。
I happen to be interested in both, and ended up enjoying the book for completely different reasons.
我碰巧对这两者都感兴趣，而最终喜欢上这本书，却是出于完全不同的原因。
Richard Thompson Ford is a law professor, and you probably won’t forget that for even one page.
理查德·汤普森·福特是一位法学教授，读这本书时，你大概每一页都会意识到这一点。
His carefully reasoned arguments, packed with examples, read almost like a court opinion, only maybe wordier.
他的论证推理缜密，又充满了例子，读起来几乎就像一份法院判决意见书，只不过可能更啰唆一些。
You will probably never think of fashion as a trifle again.
你大概再也不会把时尚看作小事一桩了。
Ford’s thesis is that the best way to understand what particular fashions meant in any given era is to look at the restrictions placed on them.
福特的论点是：要理解具体的时尚在任何特定时代意味着什么，最好的办法就是看看对它们施加了哪些限制。
Through this lens, he shows us that the first laws passed in the 1200s to ensure that only the nobility were allowed to wear certain fabrics, colors and ornaments reflected the rise of the middle class, who were now able to imitate some of these fashions.
透过这一视角，他向我们表明：13世纪，第一批法律获得通过，旨在确保只有贵族才可以穿某些面料、某些颜色的衣服，佩戴某些饰物；这些法律反映了中产阶级的崛起——此时的中产阶级已经能够模仿其中一些时尚了。
The status of the upper classes was threatened; fashion was a tool to preserve it.
上层阶级的地位受到了威胁；时尚则是维护这种地位的工具。
Ford takes the reader through the evolution of fashion while examining the underlying motivations of status, sex, power, and personality, which, he assumes, influenced all innovations in fashion in the past and which continue to influence us today.
福特带领读者纵览时尚的演变，同时审视其背后的深层动机——地位、性、权力和个性；他假定，这些动机影响了过去所有的时尚创新，并且至今仍在影响着我们。
His writing is more than a little dense—dense with research, clauses, and precise adjectives and nouns.
他的文字相当艰深——满是研究资料、从句以及精确的形容词和名词。
But there’s also humor and enough interesting episodes to make the writing appealing.
但书中也有幽默的笔触，还有足够多的有趣片段，让文字富有吸引力。
No one is spared his sharp analysis: not the easy targets of 19th-century women’s crippling fashions nor the modern uniforms of Silicon Valley T-shirts.
他犀利的分析谁也不放过：无论是19世纪女性那些伤害身体的时装这种容易攻击的靶子，还是硅谷T恤衫这种现代制服，都不例外。
But the greatest strength of this book (on fashion!) is its intellectual profoundness.
不过，这本书（讲的可是时尚！）最大的长处在于它的思想深度。
Ford asks us to question unconscious beliefs, to realize that we almost never do so, to understand that the simplest choices are charged with meaning, and yet that meaning can and does change all the time.
福特要我们去质疑无意识的信念，去认识到我们几乎从不这样做，去理解最简单的选择也充满了意义，然而这种意义随时都可能改变，而且确实一直在改变。
Consider the fact that a 1918 catalog insisted that boys and girls be dressed in the appropriate color.
想想这样一个事实吧：1918年的一份商品目录坚持要求给男孩和女孩穿上颜色合适的衣服。
We believe our thinking today is evolved; Ford shows us it’s not.
我们以为自己如今的思想已经进步了；福特却向我们表明，并非如此。